Álan Crístoffer e Sousa



Personal Data 31 years old, Brazilian

Contact +33 6 20 48 95 86

acristoffers@startmail.com https://acristoffers.me

Languages

Portuguese (native) English (C1) German (C1) French (B1)

Skills

System Analysis and Control, C/C++, Python, Kotlin, Assembly, MATLAB, Android Development, Frontend, Backend, Embedded, Automation, Robotics

Summary

Ph.D. Student and **Master of Science** in Electrical Engineering, in the field of **Control Theory**, and **Mechatronic Engineer** with experience in **system analysis and control** and **programming**. Has worked in two scientific initiations building a platform that interfaces with hardware for system analysis and control objectives and learning Model Predictive Control.

Experience

2016–2016 Acal BFi Dietzenbach, Hessen, Germany

Intern

During this internship, I developed a platform to measure the power loss inside

the kernel of the inductor used in a PFC circuit.

2010–2013 **Corpo de Bombeiros Militar de Minas Gerais** Divinópolis, Minas Gerais, Brazil

Soldier

As a firefighter I was entitled to work as a first-aider and diver, being the first response in all sorts of accidents, from fire in the wilds to car accidents and

industrial and natural disasters.

Education

2021-	Ph.D. in Ind	lustrial Automation		Univers	ité de Re	ims Cha	mpagne-Ardene,	France
		and the state of t	1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1	4.5		1 .	I a second	

I'm working on attack detection and mitigation on cyber-physical systems.

2020–2020 **Master in Electrical Engineering** CEFET-MG/UFSJ, Brazil

I developed a switching-rule for constrained switched systems based on Region of Attraction under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Valter Leite and co-supervision of Prof. Dr.

Walter Lucia.

2013–2019 **Mechatronic Engineering** Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Minas Gerais, Brazil

Since my first semester, I helped other students from graduation, master and Ph.D. with their projects, especially with programming. In my last year, I became the student

representative in the Graduation Council

2015–2016 **Student Exchange** Frankfurt University of Applied Sciences, Germany

I studied as an exchange student through the Brazilian government's program Ciências

Sem Fronteiras (Science Without Borders).

2015–2015 **Student Exchange** Université Grenoble Alpes, France

I studied as an exchange student through the partnership between UGA and CEFET-MG. There I worked in the robotics laboratory helping the team which won the second

place in the National Instruments MyRIO Paris competition.

Interests

System Analysis and Control Theory I worked with constrained switched systems and MPC. I studied non-linear and robust control, positive polynomials in control and complex networks. Now I'm working with attack detection on cyber-physical systems, researching the applicability of functional observers and time-scale systems for this end.

Programming C/C++, Python, Julia, Kotlin, Rust, Ruby, MATLAB...Languages are just tools in the belt. I can program using structured, object oriented and functional paradigms. I always try to use design patterns to make the code more organized and maintainable.

Extracurricular

EAtlaoall	iodidi				
2021	Travaux Pratiques Tutored a TP class entitled 'Mobile Programming' where I tutored students with Android application development.				
2019	BIC-Jr Cosupervisor Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'Control of a coupled tanks system'.				
2019	BIC-Jr Cosupervisor Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'Modelling of an oven with space-distributed parameters'.				
2018	BIC-Jr Cosupervisor Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'System modelling for process control'.				
2017 & 2018	Python mini-course I ministered a Python mini-course at my university. The textbook (in Portuguese) is freely available at https://acristoffers.me/Python3.pdf				
2017	Semana C&T - Week of Science and Technology My project got the first place in the 13rd workshop at my university.				
2015	National Instruments MyRIO Compatition, Paris I helped the team that got the second place in the competition. I was responsible for the code interfacing with the camera and recognizing colors.				
2014	Latin American Robotics Competition I was part of the team that got the third place in the competition. I was responsible for the circuitry and programming of one of the robots.				
2014	Programming Tutoring I tutored students, helping them with assignments and teaching.				
Publications					
2021	E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S.; LUCIA, WALTER; SILVA, LUÍS F. P. (2021). Journal of Control, Automation and Electrical Systems: Command Governor strategy based on region of attraction. (Accepted)				
2020	E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; SILVA, LUÍS F. P.; LUCIA, WALTER; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S. (2020). XXIII Congresso Brasileiro de Automática: Command Governor strategy based on region of attraction control switching.				
2020	FILHO, MARCIO R. O.; E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S.; COSTA, EMERSON S. (2020). XLI CILAMCE: Control Of An Oven With Space-Distributed Sensors.				
2019	FILHO, MARCIO R. O.; E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; COSTA, EMERSON S.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S. (2019). XL IBERO-LATIN AMERICAN CONGRESS ON COMPUTATIONAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING: Prototype Modelling for Real Systems.				
2018	E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. S.; RUBIO SCOLA, IGNACIO. Affordable Control Platform with MPC Application. Studies in Informatics and Control, v. 27, p. 265-274, 2018.				
2017	LOPES, A. N. D.; LEITE, V. J. S.; SILVA, L. F. P.; e Sousa, Álan. ESTABILIZAÇÃO LOCAL DE SISTEMAS NÃO-LINEARES VIA MODELAGEM FUZZY TAKAGI-SUGENO DISCRETA NO TEMPO. In: Simpósio Brasileiro de Automação Inteligente (SBAI), 2017, Porto Alegre - RS. XIII Simpósio Brasileiro de Automação Inteligente, 2017.				